dogstrust.org.uk 2018-01-28

# Privacy | Dogs Trust

### In safe paws

Dogs Trust takes your privacy seriously. We are committed to protecting your personal information. This policy sets out how Dogs Trust uses the information that you provide us with in order to help further our work in protecting dog welfare. 

### Cookies and Web Privacy

We at Dogs Trust guarantee our commitment to respecting and protecting your online privacy.

This includes your need and your right to know what we do with the personal information you share with us. It also guides our company's policies regarding the management of this data, including how the information is collected, processed, and for what purposes.

"Dogs Trust": refers to the web pages. By accessing this website you are consenting to the way information is collected and used, as described within this Privacy Policy. In return, Dogs Trust gives the commitment that we will use the personal data you provide only in ways that are compatible with the following Privacy Policy.

#### The collection of information

Every time you log on to our website your IP (Internet Protocol) address registers on our servers. Your IP address reveals no information other than the number assigned to you. We do not use this technology to get any personal data against your knowledge or free will (i.e., automatically recording e-mail addresses of visitors). Nor do we use it for any purpose other than to help us monitor traffic on our website, or (in case of criminal activity or misuse of our information) to cooperate with law enforcement.

#### Cookies

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance.  
The list below describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent' policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser's anonymous usage setting (called "Incognito" in Chrome, "InPrivate" for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.)

#### First Party Cookies

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information. We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are.

Find out more about [Google's position on privacy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en-GB) as regards its analytics service.

#### Third Party Cookies

These are cookies set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. Cookies of this type are the sharing buttons across the site allow visitors to share content onto social networks. Cookies are currently set by LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook, Google+ and Pinterest. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of our website. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on this website.  
You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.

#### Emails

Some emails that we send you have no tracking in at all e.g. service emails with invoices attached. Other emails we send we can track, at an individual level, whether the user has opened and clicked on the email. We do not use this information at a personal level, rather we use it to understand open and click rates on our emails to try and improve them. If you want to be sure that none of your email activity is tracked then you should opt out of our emails which you can do via the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every email we send.

#### Web Security

Financial transactions made online to Dogs Trust using this site are secure.  No one can access your credit card details via the internet.

#### How our website works

When you have completed your donation or sponsorship, your web browser will be connected directly to our secure server.  You can see that the connection is secure by looking at the padlock or key icon in the bottom left hand corner of your browser.  Your browser may also alert you to the fact that you are connecting to a secure server, and if so, it will also tell you when you are closing the secure connection once you have donated.  This is for your information only.  
Our secure server communicates with your browser using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) protocols, so that all your personal information, including credit card number and your name and address, is encrypted.  This process takes the words and figures you enter, and converts them into bits of code that are then securely transmitted over the internet.

### **Your Information – what we collect and how we use it**

Dogs Trust collects information from the public in a number of different ways.  For example, we ask for contact and other information when members of the public rehome or adopt a dog, sign up to our shared adoption scheme or engage with one of our campaigns such as our microchipping or our neutering schemes or attend a Dog School training class.  This information may include your name, date of birth and contact information.

If you are a supporter of Dogs Trust, by becoming a member, sponsoring a dog or donating to us we will ask for information that enables us to administer your donation.  This will normally include your name, contact information such as address, email or telephone number and your payment details and gift aid status.  

We also like to find out about your personal motivation for supporting us or your experience as a supporter.  This will help us to give you the information about products and services most relevant to you.  In some instances, we may carry out analysis of the personal information that you have provided to us and add publicly available information to help us tailor our communications to you.  This could include information on your interests, preferences and the level of any potential donations and can help us to improve our service and manage our contact with you in an appropriate way.

If you have given us your consent, we will contact you with information on our latest campaigns and fundraising activities. This may be by post, email, telephone or text message, depending on your preferences. We will also ask about your marketing preferences, to ensure that you are still happy to be contacted by us and by which means.

Should you wish to change your preferences you can do this by writing to us at Clarissa Baldwin House, 17 Wakley Street, London, EC1V 7RQ, by phone on 0207 837 0006 or by email addressed to [customerservices@dogstrust.org.uk](mailto:customerservices@dogstrust.org.uk)

From time to time we may contact you to ensure that the information you have provided us with remains accurate and up to date.  In some circumstances we may use external data lists to avoid misdirecting our communications with you. 

To help us communicate the work we are doing and provide these services we use trusted service providers including fundraising agencies, electronic marketing agencies and direct mailing providers.

Dogs Trust do not share, sell or swap your information with other organisations to use for their own marketing. 

In some circumstances it is necessary for Dogs Trust to give relevant staff at our service providers access to your personal information.  This access is only granted to the extent necessary for them to perform their services for us. We require all service providers to comply with strict rules to protect the information you have given us.

Like all organisations, we may comply with requests for the disclosure of personal information where this is required or permitted by law.  This could include requests from law enforcement or tax agencies. In these circumstances, the request must be submitted in writing and in accordance with the relevant legal requirements.

#### **Who we are**

By Dogs Trust and our subsidiaries we mean:The charity, Dogs Trust (registered charity numbers 227523 and SC037843);

  * Dogs Trust Trustee Limited (registered company number 08996564);
  * Dogs Trust Limited (UK registered company number 04877537 and Ireland registered company number 396919).
  * The charity, Dogs Trust Limited (Ireland) (registered charity number 20057978);
  * The charity, Dogs Trust Worldwide (registered charity numbers 1167663);
  * Dogs Trust Worldwide (registered company number 09365971);
  * Dogs Trust Promotions Limited (registered company number 00963277);

### Data Protection

All forms and transactions on this site meet with data protection requirements.  If you are making a donation or enquiring about Dogs Trust we will ask you whether you are happy to receive future mailings and updates from Dogs Trust and whether you would be happy to receive mailings from other selected charities and organisations.  If you choose not to, your name will not be put forward in this way.

By providing us with your email address you are giving us permission to contact you via email, this may be either information regarding your transaction or any promotions from Dogs Trust we feel you may be interested in. You can unsubcribe at any time using the link on the email or by calling us on 020 7837 0006.

### Information

All information given on this site is to the best of our ability.

Whilst Dogs Trust is happy to supply any assistance and guidance regarding canine welfare to Dogs Trust members and members of the public, it must be appreciated that such guidance is based only on information supplied to Dogs Trust and Dogs Trust will NOT be liable for injury, loss or damage arising from such guidance supplied.

You may print any factsheet on this site for your own information but you may NOT sell it, reproduce it on the Internet, distribute it, alter it, or reprint it in any publication without permission from the Dogs Trust Information Office.

Please note that all material on this website is the copyright of Dogs Trust or third parties. You may print any Dogs Trust factsheet on this site for your personal use, private study or for teaching purposes in schools colleges or universities provided all material is marked "By kind permission of Dogs Trust" and the material cannot be adapted for use in any other publication, used for profit or used in any way that will bring the charity into disrepute.

The name and logo of Dogs Trust are registered Trade Marks. Any use of these Trade Marks other than for private study or teaching purposes as stated above must be made with the prior express permission of Dogs Trust. If you are unsure what material you can or cannot use please contact the Digital department on 020 7837 0006.

We can only provide raffle tickets to those aged 16 and over and resident in Great Britain. Please provide your age when ordering.

### Photography

All photography on this site is reproduced with kind permission of the photographers concerned.  We would like to thank the following for the use of some of their images from time to time on this site: Adrian Brooks Photography, Alan Howard, Andy Caterall, Angus McDougall, Clifford Mason, David McNie, George Archer, Gerry Whitaker, Ian Dixon, Jason Tilley, Jason Venus, Linda Capel, Malcolm Couzens, Marc Henrie, Mike Hall, Dogs Trust Rehoming Centre Staff, Dogs Trust , Pat Doyle, Paul Fletcher, Robert Jones, Roger Richards, Tony Hall, Tim Rose, United Northern Photographers, Vicki Couchman, Wymondham Photographic, Phil Tull, Richard Murgatroyd

Updated 22nd December 2016
